# **András Gémes**

linkedin.com/gemesa Inkedin.com/gemesa Inkedin.com

# **Summary**

Embedded software engineer with 7 years of experience and a strong interest in cybersecurity, with <a href="https://hands-on experience">hands-on experience</a> in binary analysis, reverse engineering and malware analysis (specializing in Rust reversing). Certified in <a href="https://secx.ocentro.com/sec-4">Sec+</a>, <a href="https://secx.ocentro.com/sec-4">CEH, IMBT</a> and <a href="https://sec-4">PMAT</a>. Looking to apply my expertise as a reverse engineer, malware analyst or security researcher.

# Work experience

**Rust Software Engineer** @ HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary

Feb 2023 - Present

- Implementing Rust and assembly tests for the Rust compiler
- Hardening the Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Representing HighTec as a member of the LLVM security group

**Embedded Software Engineer** @ Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary

May 2018 – Jan 2023

- Implemented, automated and evaluated static application security testing (SAST)
- Configured and hardened memory and real-time operating system (RTOS) software modules
- Investigated and debugged critical software issues at the assembly level

### **Skills**

Languages: C, Rust, Python 3, Assembly (ARM64/AArch64, AMD64/x86-64), Bash

**Reverse engineering (static):** Ghidra, IDA, Joern, capa, YARA, DiE, readelf, objdump

**Reverse engineering (dynamic)**: GDB, LLDB, QEMU, strace, eBPF, VirtualBox, Qiling, Frida, x64dbg, Sysinternals

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS

Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Embedded systems and protocols: STM32, ESP32, Wi-Fi, CAN, SPI, UART, I2C

### **Certifications**

CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX, EC-Council CEH, Invoke RE IMBT and TCM Security PMAT

# **Open source contributions**

- ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches to Ghidra, focusing on the BSim, Debugger and FunctionID features
- joern: working on improved binary analysis capabilities through Ghidra integration
- ghidra-scripts: implementing custom Ghidra scripts to support reverse engineering
- rustbininfo: submitting various improvements targeting the compiler version and dependency guesser
- <u>shadow-shell</u>: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C

### **Education**

### **MSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Feb 2016 – June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

## **BSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

**Sept 2012 – Jan 2016** 

University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary

### **Continuous education**

Currently I am actively learning on TryHackMe, reading Blue Fox: Arm Assembly and managing my homelab.